A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Leadership Development Program (LDP), Accession 2017:027 FA1298
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Southwest Region LDP Fellow files, 1967-1980; 3; 7.84 Cubic Feet About 16.75 LTR size Hollinger boxes and 1 LGL size Hollinger box
  - N-S, 1967-1980; 3; 2 Cubic Feet About 4.5 LTR size Hollinger boxes
    - Paytiamo, Stanley - Acoma, New Mexico, 1967-1971 (Box 39, Folder 560-561)
    - Peso, Frederick J. - Mescalero, New Mexico, 1969-1970 (Box 39, Folder 562)
    - Peso, Frederick J. - Mescalero, New Mexico, 1969-1971 (Box 39, Folder 563)
    - Prieto, Jose V. - Marfa, Texas, 1973-1974 (Box 40, Folder 564)
    - Prieto, Jose V. - Marfa, Texas, 1973-1974 (Box 40, Folder 565)
    - Quintana, Francis - Arroyo Hondo, New Mexico, 1969-1970 (Box 40, Folder 566)
    - Quintana, Francis - Arroyo Hondo, New Mexico, 1969-1975 (Box 40, Folder 567)
    - Quintana, Joe, Jr. - Eagle Pass, Texas, 1974-1975 (Box 40, Folder 568)
    - Rodriguez, Delfino A. - Gallina, New Mexico, 1970-1980 (Box 40, Folder 569)
    - Rodriguez, Manuel M. - Wellton, Arizona, 1971-1972 (Box 40, Folder 570)
    - Romero, Benny - Las Vegas, New Mexico, 1974-1975 (Box 40, Folder 571)
    - Romero, John P. - Alamosa, Colorado, 1970-1972 (Box 40, Folder 572)
    - Romero, John P. - Alamosa, Colorado, 1970-1974 (Box 40, Folder 573)
    - Roybal, Charles - Rocky Ford, Colorado, 1974-1975 (Box 40, Folder 574)
    - Runyon, Joy C. - Whiteriver, Arizona, 1968 (Box 40, Folder 575)
      Leadership Development Program Fellows Joy C. and Kenneth V. Runyon were a married couple who received their fellowships during the same year. They engaged in both shared and separate activities, and often submitted joint reports to Southwest LDP Regional Representative/Program Consultant David Grant. Joy C. Runyon's Fellow file (folder 575) contains a Ford Foundation note that advises one to look at Kenneth V. Runyon's file for her reports.
    - Runyon, Joy C. - Whiteriver, Arizona, 1967-1968 (Box 40, Folder 576)
    - Runyon, Kenneth V. - Whiteriver, Arizona, 1967-1968 (Box 40, Folder 577)
    - Runyon, Kenneth V. - Whiteriver, Arizona, 1967-1968 (Box 40, Folder 578)
    - Sainz, Roy A. - Nogales, Arizona, 1971-1972 (Box 40, Folder 579)
    - Sainz, Roy A. - Nogales, Arizona, 1971-1974 (Box 40, Folder 580)
    - Salas, Bennie - Zia Pueblo, New Mexico, 1971 (Box 40, Folder 581)
    - Salgado, Adan C. - Valentine, Texas, 1967-1968 (Box 41, Folder 582)
    - Salgado, Adan C. - Valentine, Texas, 1967-1968 (Box 41, Folder 583)
    - Salazar, Jose H. - Santa Fe, New Mexico, 1968-1969 (Box 41, Folder 584)
    - Salazar, Jose H. - Santa Fe, New Mexico, 1968-1969 (Box 41, Folder 585)
    - Salazar, Ruby M. - Douglas, Arizona, 1973-1974 (Box 41, Folder 586)
      Within the file, materials refer to Leadership Development Program Fellow Ruby M. Salazar both by her married name, Salazar, and by her maiden name, Martin.
    - Salazar, Ruby M. - Douglas, Arizona, 1973-1974 (Box 41, Folder 587)
    - Samora, Lena C. - Monte Vista, Colorado, 1970-1972 (Box 41, Folder 588)
    - Samora, Lena C. - Monte Vista, Colorado, 1970-1971 (Box 41, Folder 589)
    - Sanchez, Clarence H. - Las Vegas, New Mexico, 1973-1974 (Box 41, Folder 590)
    - Sanchez, Narciso C., Jr. - Marfa, Texas, 1971-1972 (Box 41, Folder 591)
    - Sanchez, Narciso C., Jr. - Marfa, Texas, 1971-1972 (Box 41, Folder 592)
    - Santana, Jesse - Douglas, Arizona, 1971-1972 (Box 41, Folder 593)
    - Santana, Jesse - Douglas, Arizona, 1971-1972 (Box 41, Folder 594)
    - Sarracino, Victor A. - Old Laguna, New Mexico, 1969-1972 (Box 41, Folder 595)
    - Sarracino, Victor A. - Old Laguna, New Mexico, 1969-1972 (Box 41, Folder 596)
    - Serna, Leonila D. - Taos, New Mexico, 1972-1973 (Box 41, Folder 597)
    - Serna, Leonila D. - Taos, New Mexico, 1972-1973 (Box 41, Folder 598)
    - Sisneros, Geraldine A. - Ignacio, Colorado, 1973-1974 (Box 41, Folder 599)
    - Sisneros, Geraldine A. - Ignacio, Colorado, 1973-1974 (Box 41, Folder 600)
    - Smith, Alvin R. - Polacca, Arizona, 1967-1971 (Box 42, Folder 601)
    - Smith, Alvin R. - Polacca, Arizona, 1967-1971 (Box 42, Folder 602)
    - Smith, Diana D. - Mission, Texas, 1973-1974 (Box 42, Folder 603)
    - Smith, Diana D. - Mission, Texas, 1973-1974 (Box 42, Folder 604)
    - Soto, Nellie A. - Litchfield Park, Arizona, 1973-1974 (Box 42, Folder 605)
    - Soto, Nellie A. - Litchfield Park, Arizona, 1973-1974 (Box 42, Folder 606)
  - T-Z, 1967-1977; 4; 1 Cubic Feet About 2.25 LTR size Hollinger boxes
    Subseries contains Fellow files for Southwest Region Leadership Development Program Fellows whose last names begin with the letters T-Z.
    - Tafoya, Ramona E. - Zuni, New Mexico, 1967-1968 (Box 42, Folder 607)
      Within the file, materials refer to Leadership Development Program Fellow Ramona E. Tafoya as both Ramona Tafoya and Ramona Montelongo. Tafoya may have married during her fellowship year and adopted the name Montelongo.
    - Tafoya, Ramona E. - Zuni, New Mexico, 1967-1972 (Box 42, Folder 608)
    - Tenorio, Manuel, Jr. - Magdalena, New Mexico, 1969-1970 (Box 42, Folder 609)
    - Tenorio, Manuel, Jr. - Magdalena, New Mexico, 1969-1971 (Box 42, Folder 610)
    - Thompson, William R. - Espanola, New Mexico, 1968-1971 (Box 42, Folder 611)
    - Thompson, William R. - Espanola, New Mexico, 1968-1974 (Box 42, Folder 612-613)
    - Trujillo, Augustine - Swink, Colorado, 1972-1973 (Box 43, Folder 614)
    - Trujillo, Augustine - Swink, Colorado, 1972-1977 (Box 43, Folder 615)
    - Trujillo, J. Delfin - Tierra Amarilla, New Mexico, 1968-1970 (Box 43, Folder 616)
    - Trujillo, J. Delfin - Tierra Amarilla, New Mexico, 1968-1970 (Box 43, Folder 617)
    - Trujillo, Henry E. - Avondale, Colorado, 1967-1970 (Box 43, Folder 618)
    - Trujillo, Henry E. - Avondale, Colorado, 1967-1971 (Box 43, Folder 619)
    - Utley, Clara G. - Benavides, Texas, 1971-1972 (Box 43, Folder 620)
    - Utley, Clara G. - Benavides, Texas, 1971-1972 (Box 43, Folder 621)
    - Valdez, Alicia L. - Harquahala, Arizona, 1968-1970 (Box 43, Folder 622)
    - Valdez, Alicia L. - Harquahala, Arizona, 1968-1971 (Box 43, Folder 623)
    - Valdo, Earl M. - Acoma Reservation, New Mexico, 1970-1972 (Box 43, Folder 624)
    - Valdo, Earl M. - Acoma Reservation, New Mexico, 1970-1971 (Box 43, Folder 625)
    - Valencich, Edward F. - Tonopah, Nevada, 1967-1968 (Box 43, Folder 626)
    - Valencich, Edward F. - Tonopah, Nevada, 1967-1971 (Box 43, Folder 627)
    - Velasco, Oscar R. - Presidio, Texas, 1969-1971 (Box 43, Folder 628)
    - Velasco, Oscar R. - Presidio, Texas, 1969-1974 (Box 43, Folder 629)
    - Vigil, Gilbert A. - El Rito, New Mexico, 1969-1971 (Box 44, Folder 630)
    - Vigil, Gilbert A. - El Rito, New Mexico, 1969-1975 (Box 44, Folder 631-632)
    - Webb, L. Leon - Mesquite, Nevada, 1967-1971 (Box 44, Folder 633)
    - Webb, L. Leon - Mesquite, Nevada, 1967-1970 (Box 44, Folder 634)
    - Wells, Barbara B. - San Juan Pueblo, New Mexico, 1972-1973 (Box 44, Folder 635)
    - Wells, Barbara B. - San Juan Pueblo, New Mexico, 1972-1975 (Box 44, Folder 636)
    - Williams, Joe L. - Montrose, Colorado, 1968-1969 (Box 44, Folder 637)
    - Williams, Joe L. - Montrose, Colorado, 1968-1969 (Box 44, Folder 638)
    - Wood, Donald R. - Crownpoint, New Mexico, 1968-1970 (Box 44, Folder 639)
    - Wood, Donald R. - Crownpoint, New Mexico, 1968-1969 (Box 44, Folder 640)
    - Wright, Douglas B. - Rico, Colorado, 1969-1971 (Box 44, Folder 641)
    - Wright, Douglas B. - Rico, Colorado, 1967-1971 (Box 44, Folder 642)
      1. General Correspondence
- Southeast Region LDP Fellow files, 1960-1979; 4; 19.36 Cubic Feet About 39 LTR size Hollinger boxes and 5 LGL size Hollinger boxes
  The series consists entirely of Fellow files for the Leadership Development Program Southeast Region Office. For the most part, these files follow the general organizational scheme imposed by the records' creators for all Fellow files documenting the LDP. This means that most Southeast Region Fellows have two files for their associated records: One file holding original narrative reports submitted to Region-at-Large Regional Representative/Program Consultants Dorothy Hassfeld (1966-1968) and K.Z. Chavis (1968-1977) by the individual Fellow and one file holding narrative report copies submitted to the Ford Foundation by the Southeast office. The Southeast Region files are also comprised of the same type of content as the rest of the Fellow files found within the collection. In addition to narrative reports, they chiefly contain correspondence between the Southeast Region Office and individual Fellows, correspondence between the Southeast Region Office and Ford LDP staff, and correspondence between the Southeast Region Office and organizations that provided internships and other learning opportunities to LDP Fellows. Correspondence generally regards submissions of reports, fellowship progress, fellowship changes, and post-fellowship activities.
  The LDP Southeast Region Selection Committee recruited Fellows from the states of Alabama, Arkansas, Georgia, Florida, Mississippi, North Carolina, South Carolina, and Tennessee. It appears that the Southeast Region Office required Fellows to submit a more structured style of narrative report than those received by the other LDP Regions. This kind of report is found within many Fellow files in the series. Fellow files also hold a large quantity of fellowship application documents.
  The majority of Southeast LDP Fellows focused on developing and improving the economic, education, political, and community organization resources of African American populations. Fellow files contain records concerning the implementation and impact of school desegregation in the American South during the 1960s and 1970s. These records document many Southeast LDP Fellows' efforts to promote and protect the rights of black students in desegregated schools as well as to advocate for greater cultural awareness in teaching practices for multiracial classes. Reading skill improvement and early childhood development are other prominent education related subjects that appear within the series.
  Important African American social movements of the time are documented by more records in the series than just those concerning desegregation. Materials provide evidence of some Fellows working to protect voting rights for African Americans. Moreover, many Fellow files contain records that regard the cultural shift in African American communities when people started seeking a stronger connection to their black identities. A few of these records originate from Fellows exploring African Americans studies programs in their fellowship years.
  Lastly, many Southeast LDP Fellows worked with initiatives that sought to help African American individuals and communities cultivate economic self-sufficiency and self-empowerment. Records found within the files of these Fellows concern such subjects as agricultural cooperatives, consumer education, and vocational training.
  In addition to correspondence and reports, the Series holds newsletters, pamphlets, academic papers, press clippings, flyers, photographs, postcards, and one audio recording.
  This series was broken into four subseries during processing in order to improve user access to the large number of files produced by the Southeast Region Office.
  Series 4 Subseries 1. A-F, 1960-1978
  Series 4 Subseries 2. G-M, 1966-1978
  Series 4 Subseries 3. N-S, 1966-1978
  Series 4 Subseries 4. T-Z, 1963-1979
  - A-F, 1960-1978; 1; 3.74 Cubic Feet About 8.5 LTR size Hollinger boxes
    Subseries contains Fellow files for Southeast Region Leadership Development Program Fellows whose last names begin with the letters A-F.
    - Adams, Jacquelyn N. - Lanette, Alabama, 1966-1975 (Box 45, Folder 643)
    - Algood, Tonny H. - Laurel, Mississippi, 1972-1973 (Box 45, Folder 644)
    - Algood, Tonny H. - Laurel, Mississippi, 1971-1974 (Box 45, Folder 645-646)
    - Anderson, Anne B. - Ridgeland, South Carolina, 1973-1974 (Box 45, Folder 647)
    - Anderson, Anne B. - Ridgeland, South Carolina, 1973-1974 (Box 45, Folder 648)
    - Armour, Robert J. - Goodwater, Alabama, 1972-1973 (Box 45, Folder 649)
    - Armour, Robert J. - Goodwater, Alabama, 1972-1977 (Box 45, Folder 650-652)
    - Armster, Mae E. - Thomasville, Georgia, 1967-1968 (Box 46, Folder 653)
    - Armster, Mae E. - Thomasville, Georgia, 1966-1973 (Box 46, Folder 654-655)
    - Ash, James Wade - Carrollton, Georgia, 1966-1971 (Box 46, Folder 656)
    - Ash, James Wade - Carrollton, Georgia, 1972 (Box 46, Folder 657)
      Original folder marked "Post Fellowship"
    - Ash, James Wade - Carrollton, Georgia, 1967-1968 (Box 46, Folder 658)
    - Barnes, Barnard - Pascagoula, Mississippi, 1974-1975 (Box 46, Folder 659-660)
    - Barnett, James L. - Florence, Alabama, 1971-1972 (Box 46, Folder 661)
    - Barnett, James L. - Florence, Alabama, 1970-1977 (Box 46, Folder 662-663)
    - Bell, Marva T. - Smithdale, Mississippi, 1969-1978 (Box 47, Folder 664-665)
    - Bell, Marva T. - Smithdale, Mississippi, 1970-1971 (Box 47, Folder 666)
    - Benjamin, Lois - Atlanta, Georgia, 1970-1973 (Box 47, Folder 667)
    - Benjamin, Lois - Atlanta, Georgia, 1970-1972 (Box 47, Folder 668-669)
    - Bishop, Otto H. - Winslow, Arkansas, 1974-1975 (Box 47, Folder 670)
    - Blackmon, Michael L. - Mt. Juliet, Tennessee, 1974 (Box 47, Folder 671)
    - Bowman, Vera W. - Atlanta, Georgia, 1973-1974 (Box 47, Folder 672)
    - Bowman, Vera W. - Atlanta, Georgia, 1973-1974 (Box 47, Folder 673)
    - Braggs, Hilda F. - Moss Point, Mississippi, 1971-1977 (Box 47, Folder 674-675)
    - Braggs, Hilda F. - Moss Point, Mississippi, 1970-1973 (Box 47, Folder 676-677)
    - Bright, Britanna P. - Sumter, South Carolina, 1967-1972 (Box 48, Folder 678)
    - Bright, Britanna P. - Sumter, South Carolina, 1960-1969 (Box 48, Folder 679)
    - Brown, ReJohnna R. - Leland, Mississippi, 1971-1972; File includes three untitled still images. (Box 48, Folder 680)
    - Brown, ReJohnna R. - Leland, Mississippi, 1971-1972 (Box 48, Folder 681)
    - Bryant, John T. - Laurel, Mississippi, 1969-1970 (Box 48, Folder 682)
    - Bryant, John T. - Laurel, Mississippi, 1969-1970 (Box 48, Folder 683)
    - Bulloch, Linda R. - Atlanta, Georgia, 1970-1977 (Box 48, Folder 684-686)
    - Bulloch, Linda R. - Atlanta, Georgia, 1970-1977 (Box 48, Folder 687-688)
    - Burton, McDawson L. - Tuskegee Institute, Alabama, 1972-1975; File includes an untitled still image. (Box 48, Folder 689)
      LDP Fellow, short-term award: 1975
    - Carter, Eugene - Charleston, Mississippi, 1971-1977 (Box 48, Folder 690)
    - Carter, Eugene - Charleston, Mississippi, 1971-1973 (Box 48, Folder 691)
    - Chatman, Ronald Dean - Prichard, Alabama, 1968-1969 (Box 49, Folder 692)
    - Chatman, Ronald Dean - Prichard, Alabama, 1967-1973 (Box 49, Folder 693-694)
    - Cobb, Romelia N. - Sheffield, Alabama, 1972-1973 (Box 49, Folder 695-696)
      File includes a narrative report by Cellestine V. Hunt (nee Hill), a different Leadership Development Program Fellow. Hunt's Fellow files are located within Folders 822 and 823.
    - Cobb, Romelia N. - Sheffield, Alabama, circa 1972-1973 (Box 49, Folder 697)
      Original folder was marked "Post Fellowship Supplement Proposal"
    - Cobb, Romelia N. - Sheffield, Alabama, 1972-1975 (Box 49, Folder 698-700)
    - Conroy, Donald - South Carolina, 1971-1974 (Box 49, Folder 701)
    - Copely, Patricia A. - Bowdon, Georgia, 1971-1972 (Box 49, Folder 702)
    - Copely, Patricia A. - Bowdon, Georgia, 1971-1975 (Box 49, Folder 703)
    - Cooper, Bobby - Forest, Mississippi, 1968-1970 (Box 49, Folder 704)
    - Cooper, Bobby - Forest, Mississippi, 1967-1972 (Box 49, Folder 705-706)
    - Craig, Thelma - Yantley, Alabama, 1968 (Box 49, Folder 707)
    - Crenshaw, Doris D. - Montgomery, Alabama, 1970-1976 (Box 49, Folder 708)
    - Crenshaw, Doris D. - Montgomery, Alabama, 1970-1977 (Box 49, Folder 709)
    - Crosby, Willis H., Jr. - Greenville, South Carolina, 1972-1977 (Box 50, Folder 710-714)
      File contains documents concerning the development of Leadership University. Post Leadership Development Program Fellows in the Southeast Region envisioned Leadership University as a way to share their collective resources and skills. The University was committed to the pursuit of equal educational opportunity and equal civic participation for all members of society.
      File also include a July 4, 1974 issue of the magazine "Jet" (Folder 711).
    - Crosby, Willis H., Jr. - Greenville, South Carolina, 1973-1974 (Box 50, Folder 715)
    - Delaney, Joseph D. - Grenada, Mississippi, 1968-1969 (Box 50, Folder 716)
      File includes a narrative report by Bobby Cooper a different Leadership Development Program Fellow. Cooper's Fellow files are located within Folders 704-706.
    - Delaney, Joseph D. - Grenada, Mississippi, 1968-1977 (Box 50, Folder 717-718)
    - Doe, Patrick A. - Burton, South Carolina, 1968-1971 (Box 50, Folder 719)
    - Doe, Patrick A. - Burton, South Carolina, 1967-1975 (Box 50, Folder 720)
    - Dorsey, S. J. - Carrollton, Georgia, 1967-1977 (Box 51, Folder 721-723)
    - Dorsey, S. J. - Carrollton, Georgia, 1968-1971 (Box 51, Folder 724)
    - Duffey, Carol - Carrollton, Georgia, 1971-1972 (Box 51, Folder 725-727)
    - Duffey, Carol - Carrollton, Georgia, 1975 (Box 51, Folder 728)
      Original folder was marked as "Post Fellowship Supplement Proposal"
    - Duffey, Carol - Carrollton, Georgia, 1971-1975; File includes two still images (Folder 730). One depicts a classroom and the other is titled Upward Bound, Vance Hall, UNC. (Box 51, Folder 729-732)
      An untitled still image has been removed from the file (Folder 730) for stabilization.
    - Durden, John, Jr. - Eastanollee, Georgia, 1968-1969 (Box 52, Folder 733)
      LDP Fellow, short-term: 1968
    - Dyer, Bernard N. - Miami, Florida, 1974-1975 (Box 52, Folder 734)
      Within the original folder, another folder marked "Bernard Dyer" had been inserted to become part of the overall file.
    - Dyson, Willie W. - Waycross, Georgia, 1969-1975 (Box 52, Folder 735-736)
    - Dyson, Willie W. - Waycross, Georgia, 1969-1971 (Box 52, Folder 737)
    - Elrod, Lu - Chamblee, Georgia, 1968-1969 (Box 52, Folder 738)
    - Elrod, Lu - Chamblee, Georgia, 1967-1975 (Box 52, Folder 739)
    - Evans, James C. - Georgetown, South Carolina, 1971-1977 (Box 52, Folder 740-741)
    - Evans, James C. - Georgetown, South Carolina, 1971-1972 (Box 52, Folder 742)
    - Fant, Elizabeth F. - Belton, South Carolina, 1973-1975 (Box 52, Folder 743)
    - Fant, Elizabeth F. - Belton, South Carolina, 1973-1976 (Box 52, Folder 744-745)
    - Foard, Kay F. - Moss Point, Mississippi, 1973-1977 (Box 53, Folder 746-747)
    - Foard, Kay F. - Moss Point, Mississippi, 1973-1974 (Box 53, Folder 748)
    - Frazier, Hazel L. - Beaufort, South Carolina, 1971-1977 (Box 53, Folder 749)
    - Frazier, Hazel L. - Beaufort, South Carolina, 1971 (Box 53, Folder 750)
    - Fredd, Chester A., Jr. - Tuscaloosa, Alabama, 1970-1971 (Box 53, Folder 751)
    - Fredd, Chester A., Jr. - Tuscaloosa, Alabama, 1966-1977 (Box 53, Folder 752-753)
  - G-M, 1966-1978; 2; 8.25 Cubic Feet About 18.75 LTR size Hollinger boxes
    Subseries contains Fellow files for Southeast Region Leadership Development Program Fellows whose last names begin with the letters G-M.
    - Gadson, Carrienelle F. - Tuskegee Institute, Alabama, 1967-1968 (Box 53, Folder 754)
    - Gadson, Carrienelle F. - Tuskegee Institute, Alabama, 1967-1976 (Box 53, Folder 755)
    - George, Stine P. - Donalsonville, Georgia, 1968-1976 (Box 53, Folder 756)
    - George, Stine P. - Donalsonville, Georgia, 1967-1976; Files includes a set of three still images (Folder 757) and another two individual still images (Folder 757). The set of three is titled Seminole County Training School Shop and the other two are titled Seminole County Training School and House in Seminole County near Rail Road tracks respectively. (Box 53, Folder 757-758)
    - Gill, Luke K., Jr. - Manchester, Georgia, 1969-1975; File includes a still image of LDP Fellow Luke K. Gill Jr. (Folder 759). (Box 53, Folder 759-760)
    - Gill, Luke K., Jr. - Manchester, Georgia, 1969-1975 (Box 53, Folder 761)
    - Good, Georgia S. - Orangeburg, South Carolina, 1970-1974 (Box 54, Folder 762)
    - Good, Georgia S. - Orangeburg, South Carolina, 1969-1976 (Box 54, Folder 763)
    - Grant, William - Burton, South Carolina, 1969-1975 (Box 54, Folder 764-765)
      Within the original folder, another folder marked "William Grant -- documentary papers, Shaw U.W.W." had been inserted to become part of the overall file.
    - Gunn, Howard L. - Okolona, Mississippi, 1972-1976 (Box 54, Folder 766-767)
    - Gunn, Howard L. - Okolona, Mississippi, 1973-1975 (Box 54, Folder 768)
    - Hadnott, James O. - Prattville, Alabama, 1973-1977 (Box 54, Folder 769-771)
    - Hadnott, James O. - Prattville, Alabama, 1973-1974 (Box 54, Folder 772-773)
    - Hadnott, Sallie M. - Prattville, Alabama, 1971-1972 (Box 55, Folder 774)
    - Hadnott, Sallie M. - Prattville, Alabama, 1971-1977 (Box 55, Folder 775)
    - Hargrove, Jean H. - Montgomery, Alabama, 1970-1973 (Box 55, Folder 776-777)
    - Hargrove, Jean H. - Montgomery, Alabama, 1971-1973 (Box 55, Folder 778)
    - Harper, Consuelo J. - Shorter, Alabama, 1967-1975 (Box 55, Folder 779-781)
    - Harper, Consuelo J. - Shorter, Alabama, 1966-1976 (Box 55, Folder 782-785)
      Within the original folder, another folder marked "Connie Harper" had been inserted to become part of the overall file.
    - Harris, Albert L., Jr. - Montgomery, Alabama, 1975-1977 (Box 56, Folder 786-787)
      LDP Fellow: 1975-1976
      Within the original folder, another folder marked "Albert L. Harris" had been inserted to become part of the overall file.
    - Harris, Joseph L. - Indianola, Mississippi, 1972-1975 (Box 56, Folder 788-790)
      Within the original folder, two other folders had been inserted to become part of the overall file. The first was unmarked. The second was labelled "Joe Harris - 1st and 2nd".
    - Harris, Joseph L. - Indianola, Mississippi, 1973-1974 (Box 56, Folder 791)
    - Harrison, Ezekiel - Tuscaloosa, Alabama, 1969-1971 (Box 56, Folder 792)
    - Harrison, Ezekiel - Tuscaloosa, Alabama, 1969-1977; File includes a still image of LDP Fellow Ezekiel Harrison (Folder 793). (Box 56, Folder 793-794)
    - Harvey, Boss E. - Jackson, Mississippi, 1973-1974 (Box 57, Folder 795)
    - Harvey, Boss E. - Jackson, Mississippi, 1968-1975 (Box 57, Folder 796-797)
    - Haynes, Odell S. - Salem, Alabama, 1974-1976 (Box 57, Folder 798-799)
      Within the original folder, another folder marked "Odell S. Haynes" had been inserted to become part of the overall file.
    - Heggins, Martha J.A. - Orangeburg, South Carolina, 1967-1975 (Box 57, Folder 800)
    - Heggins, Martha J.A. - Orangeburg, South Carolina, 1973-1975 (Box 57, Folder 801-802)
      Original folder was marked "Martha J. A. Heggins -- Post Fellowship Supplement"
    - Heggins, Martha J.A. - Orangeburg, South Carolina, 1967-1976 (Box 57, Folder 803-804)
    - Hegmon, Doris J. - Montgomery, Alabama, 1970-1974 (Box 58, Folder 805)
      LDP Fellow, short-term award: 1970-1971
    - Hegmon, Doris J. - Montgomery, Alabama, 1969-1974 (Box 58, Folder 806-807)
      An untitled still image has been removed from the file (Folder 806) for stabilization.
    - Hewlett, Marshall T. - Pascagoula, Mississippi, 1974-1975 (Box 58, Folder 808)
    - Hewlett, Marshall T. - Pascagoula, Mississippi, circa 1974-1975 (Box 58, Folder 809)
    - Hillman, Mary Sue - Leakesville, Mississippi, 1971-1974 (Box 58, Folder 810)
      LDP Fellow, short-term award: 1971-1972
    - Hillman, Mary Sue - Leakesville, Mississippi, 1971-1975 (Box 58, Folder 811-812)